二零二三年怀化市初中毕业学业水平考试
英语听力第一部分听力技能。
做题时，先将答案标在试卷上。
上录音内容结束后，你将有两分钟的时间将试卷上的答案转涂到答题卡上
第一节，听下面五段对话，每段对话后有一个小题，从题中所给的。
,B What's your favorite sport, Robert?
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听完每段对话后，你将有十秒钟的时间来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题。
每段对话读两遍。
Basketball What's your favorite sport, Robert?
Basketball Three. Lily, can you play the piano?
No, I can't.
I can play the guitar.
Lily, can you play the piano?
No, I can't.
I can play the guitar.
Four. What time do you usually get to school every morning, Frank?
At 7.30.
What time do you usually get to school every morning, Frank?
Five. Is there a supermarket near here?
Yes, there is.
It's next to the bank.
Is there a supermarket near here?
Yes, there is.
It's next to the bank.
第二节，听下面五段对话或独白，每段对话或独白后有几个小题，从题中
所给的
B, How was your trip last week, Lucy?
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听每段对话或独白前，你将有时间阅读各个小题，每小题五秒钟。
听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。
每段对话或独白读。
读两遍。
听第六段材料，回答第六至七题。
It was excellent.
I visited my uncle in the countryside.
Oh, nice. What did you do?
I fed the chickens.
How was your trip last week, Lucy?
It was excellent.
I visited my uncle in the countryside.
Oh, nice. What did you do?
I fed the chickens.
听第七段材料，回答第。
Can you come to my party on Monday, Lisa?
My cousin will come here from Changsha.
I'd love to, Mike, but I have an exam.
That's too bad.
Can you go to the movies with us on Sunday?
Okay, see you then.
Can you come to my party on Monday, Lisa?
My cousin will come here from Changsha.
I'd love to, Mike, but I have an exam.
That's too bad.
Can you go to the movies with us on Sunday?
Okay, see you then.
听第八段材料，回答第十至十二题。
我。
did you do at home,
I talked about TV shows with my father.
He loves sports shows.
How about you, Jack?
I like news.
Well, I don't like news.
My favorite is talk shows.
I think they're boring.
Well, but we can learn a lot from them.
What do you want to be one day?
I hope to be a reporter.
What did you do at home,
I talked about TV shows with my father.
He loves sports shows.
How about you, Jack?
I like news.
Well, I don't like news.
My favorite is talk shows.
I think they're boring.
Well, but we can learn a lot from them.
What do you want to be one day?
I hope to be a reporter.
听第九段材料，回答第十三至十六题。
What are you doing, Peter?
I'm reading books.
Next week, I will tell some stories to my classmates.
Sounds great. I think you must be good at writing, right?
Yes. I like writing very much.
Do you want to be a writer?
Yes, I do.
To be a writer, I keep on writing stories.
How about you, Linda?
I want to be a doctor because I can help people and I hope to live in Shanghai.
That's great. Try our best and our dreams will come true.
Yes, you're right.
What are you doing, Peter?
I'm reading books.
Next week, I will tell some stories to my classmates.
Sounds great. I think you must be good at writing, right?
Yes. I like writing very much.
Do you want to be a writer?
Yes, I do.
To be a writer, I keep on writing stories.
How about you, Linda?
I want to be a doctor because I can help people and I hope to live in That's great.
Try our best and our dreams will come true.
Yes, you're right.
听第十段材料，回答第十七至二十题。
Dear Mom, I'd like to tell you something.
I'm 16 years old now.
I think I am old enough to make some pocket money by myself.
Summer vacation is coming.
I want to get a job.
I know that your restaurant needs workers.
Can I have a job at your restaurant?
So I can make some pocket money.
I can work as a waiter or a cleaner.
Now, many students go to work during the summer vacation.
They get jobs in restaurants or supermarkets.
They make pocket money by themselves.
I hope you can give me a chance, okay?
Your son, Lihua.
Dear Mom, I'd like to tell you something.
I'm 16 years old now.
I think I am old enough to make some pocket money by myself.
Summer vacation is coming.
I want to get a job.
I know that your restaurant needs workers.
Can I have a job at your restaurant?
So I can make some pocket money.
I can work as a waiter or a cleaner.
Now, many students go to work during the summer vacation.
They get jobs in restaurants or supermarkets.
They make pocket money by themselves.
I hope you can give me a chance, okay?
Your son, Lihua.
听力考试到此结束。
现在你有两分钟的时间，将试卷上的答案转涂到答题卡上。